Koushal Rathor

Professional Summary:

Phone: 9782175002

Address: Jaipur , Rajasthan,302022

Email: koushalrathor@gmail.com

Passionate and highly effective Team Lead successful at building Android applications and managing the Android Development team. Well-educated and poised with 9+ years of expertise. Trained in Android Application Development with experience in performing quality inspections.

EXPERIENCE

Ahead WebSoft Technologies Pvt Ltd

Sept 2020 - Present

Team Lead

Reported on updates to project specifications and progress.

Minimized resource and time losses by addressing employee or production issue directly and implementing timely solutions.

Continuously checked products for quality assurance according to strict guidelines.

Managed schedules, accepted time off requests and found coverage for short shifts.

Maintained comprehensive knowledge of mobile development cycle and addressed challenges arising in each phase.

Worked with teams from other projects and departments to create apps driven by customer input.

Managed aspects of Android app lifecycle from research and planning through deployment and post-launch support.

Successfully integrated push notifications into apps, bolstering user engagement.

Provided dedicated support and timely issue resolution to clients following successful app launch.

Collaborated with cross-functional teams to define and design new features.

Used specific code versioning tools to manage and implement changes to programs.

Tested applications prior to final review to verify issue resolution.

Consistently used Android SDK to produce highly effective and nuanced content.

Devised techniques for better modularity, testability and maintainability of front-end applications.

Supported team members with one-on-one and group trainings.

Analyzed applications to identify and document weaknesses and errors.

B2CVertical Jan 2019 - Sept 2020

TEAM LEAD

Reported on updates to project specifications and progress.

Minimized resource and time losses by addressing employee or production issue directly and implementing timely solutions.

Tracked receipts, employee hours and inventory movements.

Managed schedules, accepted time off requests and found coverage for short shifts.

Established open and professional relationships with team members to achieve quick resolutions for various issues.

Continuously checked products for quality assurance according to strict quidelines.

Handled troubleshooting tasks and used repair methods to immediately rectify assembly line issues.

Sag Infotech Pvt Ltd Apr 2018- Dec 2018

Team Lead

Reported on updates to project specifications and progress.

Minimized resource and time losses by addressing employee or production issue directly and implementing timely solutions.

Maintained comprehensive knowledge of mobile development cycle and addressed challenges arising in each phase.

Worked with teams from other projects and departments to create apps driven by customer input.

Supported team members with one-on-one and group trainings.

Managed aspects of Android app lifecycle from research and planning through deployment and post-launch support.

Sag Infotech Pvt Ltd

Nov 2016 - Mar 2018

Senior Android Developer

Designed user interfaces that engaged multiple senses and produced immersive experiences.

Devised documentation for each app, detailing operation aspects, functions, capabilities and features.

Successfully integrated push notifications into apps, bolstering user engagement.

Used specific code versioning tools to manage and implement changes to programs.

Supported team members with one-on-one and group trainings.

Consistently used Android SDK to produce highly effective and nuanced content.

Employed third-party APIs to facilitate seamless access to external, in-app cloud data.

The Whole Digidoodle Pvt Ltd

Jan 2015 - Nov 2016

Android Developer

Designed user interfaces that engaged multiple senses and produced immersive experiences.

Devised documentation for each app, detailing operation aspects, functions, capabilities and features.

Successfully integrated push notifications into apps, bolstering user engagement.

Used third-party libraries, custom libraries and APIs to develop new applications.

Employed third-party APIs to facilitate seamless access to external, in-app cloud data.

Tested applications prior to final review to verify issue resolution.

Pericent Technologies

Nov 2013 - Jan 2015

Android Developer

Designed user interfaces that engaged multiple senses and produced immersive experiences.

Managed aspects of Android app lifecycle from research and planning through deployment and post-launch support.

Created custom mobile applications using native technologies.

Consistently used Android SDK to produce highly effective and nuanced content.

Tested applications prior to final review to verify issue resolution.

EDUCATION

Rajasthan Technical University

Sep 2009-May 2013

B.Tech

SKILLS

Quality control

Technical Support

Creativity

Problem-Solving

Bug resolution

Programming

Testing and maintenance

Code reviews

Team Management

PROJECTS

Inbook

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=in.inbook.app

Wegotups

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.wegotups.app

Clone book

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.clonebook

Sema social

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.semasocial

Afrosky

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.new.afrosky

Ciclou

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.ciclou.city.cloud

Flooco

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.flooco

Pitchit.fun

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.pitchit

Nursing Network

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=eu.NursingNetwork

Advice Tank: - Online Learning

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.advicetank

Phantom

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.agency55.phantom

Decathlon Camp

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.decathlon.camp

GreenMoov' Manager

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.agency55.gmmanager

Mobo Tour

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=and.mobo.tour&hl=en

PayRoll

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.sag.payroll

Let's Live - Social / Local /

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.letslive

My Ciircle: Learning Social Networks

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.agency.myciircle

iNotice

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.agency55.inotice

Autogenys

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.agency55.autogenys

La Mano Verde

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.agency55.lamanoverde

SAMY Guide - Manage your account

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.agency55.samyguide

NetWorkOut

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.agency.nwo

Magic English – Learn English fast

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.agency55.magicenglish

Namaste India

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.twd.namsteyindia

Pizzeria Pierrofino

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.firstweb.pierrofino

iSafety

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.firstweb.safetyapp

New Bright Wash

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.twd.bright_wash

Currency Convertor

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.yashawi.currencyconverter&hl=en

Rambagh Golf Club

https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.rambagh_sag.golfclub

Note: Handled more than 90+ projects so far in my 9+ years of career.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Language

Android, Kotlin , Tizen , Java (Core), C , C++,PHP,XML,Flutter

Database Language

My SQL, Ormlite, ORACLE

Operating System

Windows XP/7

Web Languages

HTML, CSS with JAVA Script, Hibernate, J query, Servlets